aucklandcouncil.govt.nz 2018-08-17

# Website privacy policy

The privacy of your personal information is important to us. 

## Customer Privacy Policy

Our Customer Privacy Policy sets out how we collect, use, protect and share your personal information. It incorporates the requirements set out in the Privacy Act 1993. 

The Privacy Act is supervised by the [ New Zealand Privacy Commissioner](http://www.privacy.org.nz/). 

## Collection and use of personal information on this website

Personal information that is already held in public records may be accessible on this website and subsidiary websites. 

An example is minutes of council meetings which record submissions or deputations that are made by members of the public. 

###  Consents

We need the information you provide on a building consent application form to process the application under the Building Act 2004. 

We collate statistics relating to issued building consents and have a statutory obligation to regularly forward these to Statistics New Zealand. 

We store the information on a public register. We must supply this information (as previously determined by the Office of the Ombudsmen) to whomsoever requests the information. 

Under the Privacy Act 1993 you have the right to see and correct personal information we hold about you.  

##  Storage and security of personal information

When any online services are provided which involve visitors sending personal financial information to this website and subsidiary websites, a secure transmission method will be used. 

All Auckland Council employees and data processors who have access to, and are associated with the processing of, personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data. 

##  Meeting webcasts

To keep Aucklanders up to date on our activities, we are filming some of our meetings. 

You will know which meetings are being filmed as there will be a sign clearly stating this before you enter into the meeting room. 

We will broadcast the footage live online and recordings will be available on our website. 

Most of the filming will cover elected members as they speak and debate at the meeting. 

The filming may also include shots of the public in the background and anyone speaking at public forum. 

When filming meetings, we may collect, store and publish personal information about people attending the meetings. This is because personal information can include a person’s voice or image. 

To minimise any unnecessary collection of material, we will follow our protocols for webcasting meetings. 

Where we do collect personal information (by filming a person’s face or voice), we will collect, store and publish that personal information in accordance with our privacy policy on this page: 

  * We are filming meetings as it in the public interest to have transparent and accessible decision-making at public meetings. 
  * The intended recipients of the information are the general public who can access the footage on our website. In other words, the footage will be publicly available. 
  * The name and address of the agency that is collecting the information; and the agency that will hold the information is Auckland Council, through its agent Tandem Studios. 

If you have any questions or concerns on the filmed footage, contact Auckland Council Privacy Officers: 

Auckland Council Privacy Officers  
Private Bag 92300  
Victoria Street  
Auckland 1142. 

This applies only to Auckland Council meeting footage, not to footage taken by any other entity (including the media).
